Inventory of the Charles Patrick Carroll papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Charles Patrick Carroll papers
1809-1999
2001C76
Hoover Institution Archives
73 manuscript boxes (29.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, notes, conference papers, and printed matter, relating to medical ethics, and to medical, legal, moral and theological aspects of euthanasia, sterilization, abortion, assisted suicide, and related issues. Includes copies of transcripts of war crime trials of Nazi doctors at Nuremberg.
Carroll, Charles Patrick.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2001.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1916 Born, Kansas City, Missouri
1937-1938 Student, Berlin, Germany
1939 B.A., Yale University
1945-1947 Teaching fellow, Department of Government, Harvard University
1947-1948 Official observer, U.S. vs. Karl Brandt, et al.
1947-1948 Assistant to the Director of the Civil Administration Division, Office of Military Government, United States
1951 Ordained, Episcopal Church
1967-1971 Protestant Chaplain, University of California-San Francisco Medical Center
1972 Author, "Medicine without an Ethic," Journal of the Louisiana State Medical Society
1972-2002 Researched German medicine from 1895-1945
1985 Board of Advisors, National Organization of Episcopalians for Life
1994 Author, "Judeo-Christian View of Man's Nature Confirmed at Auschwitz," Colorado Springs Gazette Telegraph
1995 Author, "Nuremberg Judgment and Challenge: The Rediscovery of the Law above the Statutory," Journal of Legal Studies
2004 Died, Colorado
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains correspondence, notes, conference papers, and printed matter, relating to medical ethics, euthanasia, sterilization, abortion, assisted suicide, and related issues. The bulk of the papers consists of research materials Carroll collected from 1972-2002 on German medicine, euthanasia, and the Holocaust.
Abortion.; Assisted suicide.; Eugenics.; Euthanasia.; Genocide.; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Medical ethics.; Nuremberg Medical Trial, Nuremberg, Germany, 1946-1947.; Sterilization, Eugenic.
- Nuremberg War Crime Trials transcripts, 1946-1947
  Note
  Photocopies of official transcripts with annotations by Carroll
  - U.S. vs. Karl Brandt, et al., 1933-1947
    - Prosecution, 1946-1947
      - Opening statements, 1946-1947 (Box 1)
      - Euthanasia program, 1947 (Box 1)
      - Freezing experiments, 1946 (Box 1)
      - Tubercular Poles program, 1946 (Box 1)
      - Jewish skeletons collection, 1946 (Box 1)
      - Low pressure experiments, 1946 (Box 1)
      - Sulfanilamide and bone/muscle experiments, 1946 (Box 1)
      - Malaria experiments, 1946 (Box 1)
      - Polygal and phlegmon experiments, 1947 (Box 1)
      - Sterilization experiments, 1947 (Box 1)
    - Defense, 1947
      - Fischer, Fritz, 1947 (Box 1)
      - Gebhardt, Karl, 1940-1947 (Box 1)
      - Genzken, Karl, 1947 (Box 1)
      - Hoven, Waldemar, 1947 (Box 1)
      - Rostock, Paul, 1947 (Box 1)
      - Schäfer, Konrad, 1947 (Box 1)
      - Schröder, Oskar, 1944-1947 (Box 1)
      - Becker-Feryseng, Hermann, 1947 (Box 2)
      - Beiglböck, Wilhelm, 1947 (Box 2)
      - Brack, Viktor, 1947 (Box 2)
      - Schäfer, Konrad, 1947 (Box 2)
      - Blome, Kurt, 1947 (Box 3)
      - Brack, Viktor, 1947 (Box 3)
      - Brandt, Karl, 1947 (Box 3)
      - Brandt, Rudolf, 1947 (Box 3)
      - Mrugowsky, Joachim, 1947 (Box 3)
      - Oberheuser, Herta, 1947 (Box 3)
      - Poppendick, Helmut, 1947 (Box 3)
      - Romberg, Hans-Wolfgang, 1947 (Box 3)
      - Ruff, Siegfried, 1947 (Box 3)
      - Sievers, Wolfram, 1947 (Box 3)
      - Weltz, Georg August, 1947 (Box 3)
    - Document books
      - Becker-Freyseng, Hermann, 1946-1947 (Box 4)
      - Beiglböck, Wilhelm, 1933-1947 (Box 4)
      - Brandt, Rudolf, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Gebhardt, Karl, Herta Oberheuser, and Fritz Fischer, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Genzken, Karl, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Mrugowsky, Joachim, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Poppendick, Helmut, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Romberg, Hans Wolfgang, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Schäfer, Konrad, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Hoven, Waldemar, 1942-1947 (Box 5)
      - Pokorny, Adolf, 1947 (Box 5)
      - Rose, Gerhard, 1943-1947 (Box 5)
      - Rostock, Paul, 1945-1947 (Box 5)
      - Ruff, Siegfried, 1946-1947 (Box 5)
      - Schröder, Oskar, 1946-1947 (Box 5)
      - Weltz, Georg August, 1942-1947 (Box 5)
      - Brack, Viktor, 1947 (Box 6)
      - Brandt, Karl, 1947 (Box 6)
      - Handloser, Siegfried, 1947 (Box 6)
      - Sievers, Wolfram, 1947 (Box 6)
      - Gerstein Report (Box 6)
      - Photographs of experimentation subjects at Buchenwald and Dachau (Box 6)
      - Document books 1-2 (Box 6)
      - Document books 3-18 (Box 7)
      - German document books (Box 8)
        Scope and Contents note
        Photocopy of pages 9485-11403
    - Closing briefs, 1947
      - Becker-Freyseng, Hermann, 1947 (Box 9)
      - Beiglböck, Wilhelm (Box 9)
      - Blome, Kurt, 1947 (Box 9)
      - Brack, Viktor, 1947 (Box 9)
      - Brandt, Kurt, 1947 (Box 9)
      - Brandt, Rudolf, 1947 (Box 9)
      - Fischer, Fritz, 1947 (Box 10)
      - Gebhardt, Karl, 1947 (Box 10)
      - Genzken, Karl, 1947 (Box 10)
      - Handloser, Siegfried, 1947 (Box 10)
      - Hoven, Waldemar, 1947 (Box 11)
      - Mrugowsky, Joachim, 1947 (Box 11)
      - Oberheuser, Herta, 1947 (Box 11)
      - Pokorny, Adolf, 1947 (Box 11)
      - Poppendick, Helmut, 1947 (Box 11)
      - Romberg, Hans-Wolfgang, Siegfried Ruff, and Georg August Weltz, 1947 (Box 11)
      - Rose, Gerhard, 1947 (Box 11)
      - Rostock, Paul, 1947 (Box 11)
      - Schäfer, Konrad, 1947 (Box 11)
      - Schroeder, Oskar, 1947 (Box 11)
      - Sievers, Wolfram, 1947 (Box 11)
      - Weltz, Georg, 1947 (Box 11)
      - Closing argument for the United States, 1947 (Box 11)
  - U.S. vs. Josef Altstoetter, et al., 1947 (Box 12)
  - U.S. vs. Oswald Pohl, et al., 1947 (Box 12)
  - U.S. vs. Ulrich Greifelt, et al., 1947-1948 (Box 12)
    Trial for officials of the Rasse- und Siedlungshauptamt-SS (RuShA)
  - U.S. vs. Wilhelm von Leeb, et al., 1947-1948 (Boxes 12-13)
- Research materials
  Comprised mainly of photocopies of printed matter. Any folders with correspondence or writings by Carroll are noted
  - Abortion
    - Abortion in West Germany, 1975-1993 (Box 14)
    - Fetal experimentation, 1971-1990 (Box 14)
    - Fetal rights, 1972-1991 (Box 14)
    - Feticide, 1972-1991 (Box 14)
    - Fetology, 1965-1993 (Box 14)
    - Infant mortality, 1973-1975 (Box 14)
    - Infanticide, 1971-1986 (Box 14)
    - Legal abortion, 1967-1975 (Box 14)
    - Nader, Ralph, 1972 (Box 14)
    - Nagengast, Karl, 1954 (Box 14)
    - National Conferences of Catholic Bishops, 1974-1988 (Box 14)
    - National Council of Churches, 1983 (Box 14)
    - National health insurance proposals, 1974 (Box 14)
    - National Organization of Episcopalians for Life, 1988 (Box 14)
    - Needleman, Jacob, 1970 (Box 14)
    - Newborns, 1981-1987 (Box 14)
    - Surrogate mothers, 1979-1987 (Box 14)
  - Academic freedom, 1980 (Box 15)
  - Architecture, 1974 (Box 15)
  - Arendt, Hannah, 1974 (Box 15)
  - Armenian Holocaust, 1915-1983 (Box 15)
  - Art, 1955-1992 (Box 15)
  - Auschwitz survivors, 1993 (Box 15)
  - "Baby Doe" and related cases, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Barbie, Klaus, 1983-1987 (Box 15)
  - Hartl, Albert, 1947 (Box 15)
  - Experimentation on prisoners
    - Japan, 1975 (Box 15)
    - Phosphorus Experiments in Sachsenhausen and Auschwitz, 1943 (Box 15)
    - Infektionsversuche an Menschen, dissertation by Alfred Heilbrunn, 1937, 1977 (Box 15)
    - Rose, Gerhard, 1944-1979 (Box 15)
      Includes correspondence between Carroll and Rose, one of the doctors convicted of war crimes at Nuremberg
  - Holocaust
    - Eichmann, Adolf, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Enlightenment, 1975-1997 (Box 15)
    - Film, 1977-1984 (Box 15)
    - The Gentile Holocaust, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Gerettet vor dem Holocaust, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Guilt, 1978-1982 (Box 15)
    - Heroes, 1943-1998 (Box 15)
    - History, 1952-1994 (Box 15)
    - In memory, 1982-1984 (Box 15)
    - International Conference on the Holocaust and Genocide, 1980-1997 (Box 15)
      Includes essay by Carroll about the 1982 conference
  - Ecology, 1967-1972 (Box 16)
  - Euthanasia
    - "Authentischer Bericht über die Menschenvernichtung im Schloss Hartheim", 1969 (Box 16)
    - Book review, Die Freigabe der Vernichtung lebensunwerten Lebens, 1922 (Box 16)
    - Eser, Albin, "Suizid und Euthanasie als human- und sozialwissenschaftliches Problem", 1976 (Box 16)
    - Hoche, Alfred, et. al, Die Freigabe der Vernichtung lebensunwerten Lebens, 1920 (Box 16)
    - Jost, Adolf, Das Recht auf den Tod: Sociale Studie, 1895 (Box 16)
    - Lex Vitae, Americans United for Life, 1977 (Box 16)
    - Mann, Ernst, "Die Erlösung der Menschheit vom Elend", 1922 (Box 16)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 16)
    - Niedermeyer, Albert, Sterben und Tod: (Euthanasie, Thanatologie), 1952 (Box 16)
    - Psychiatrisch-Neurologische Wochenschrift, excerpts, 1912-1913 (Box 16)
    - Animals, 1872-1987 (Box 17)
    - "Liste der deutschen Anstalten für Geisteskranke und Schwachsinnige per 31.8.41," Zentrale Stelle der Landesjustizverwaltungen, Ludwigsburg, 1941 (Box 17)
    - Psychological, 1941-1972 (Box 17)
    - Rhetoric, 1973-1995 (Box 17)
    - Right to die, 1975-1993 (Box 17)
    - Straus, Walter, "Medical Ethics and Racial Ideology in the Nazi Euthanasia Program", 1974 (Box 17)
    - Warmund, Erich (pseudonym of Joseph Mayer), "Euthanasie im Lichte der katholischen Moral und Praxis", 1940 (Box 17)
    - Watson, James D., 1973 (Box 17)
    - Weissman, Gerald, 1985 (Box 17)
    - Weizsäcker, Viktor von, "Euthanasie und Menschenversuche", 1947 (Box 17)
    - Wimmer, August, "Kein Recht auf den eigenen Tod?", 1975 (Box 17)
  - Fluoride, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Food production, 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Forster, E.M., 1952-1987 (Box 18)
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1977 (Box 18)
  - Freedom and planning, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Freedom of speech, 1968-1972 (Box 18)
  - Futurology, 1969-1982 (Box 18)
  - Genetics
    - Ethical, 1968-1976 (Box 18)
    - Legal, 1970 (Box 18)
    - Artificial insemination, 1970-1972 (Box 18)
    - Cleansing gene pool, 1969-1973 (Box 18)
    - Scientific, 1967-1989 (Box 18)
    - Genetic screening, 1972-1990 (Box 18)
    - Racial (sickle anemia and cystic fibrosis), 1971-1976 (Box 18)
  - Genetic engineering, 1970-1998 (Box 18)
  - Genocide, 1973-1990 (Box 18)
  - Evangelische Kirche in Deutschland, 1945 (Box 19)
  - Expulsion of citizens from Alsace, asocials, etc. (Box 19)
  - Faulhaber, Michael von. "Kardinal Faulhaber: Kämpfer oder Mitläufer?" Frankfurter Hefte, 1966 (Box 19)
  - Fazit: kein Rechtfertigungsversuch, by Melita Maschmann, 1964 (Box 19)
  - Flossenburg (Box 19)
  - Food for youth in war, 1944 (Box 19)
    Report from the Reichsministerium für Ernährung und Landwirtschaft (RMEL)
  - Holocaust
    - Consequences, 1976-1992 (Box 19)
    - Defamation, 1978-1987 (Box 19)
    - Denazification, Joe Napoli, 1980-1983 (Box 19)
    - Auschwitz, 1970-1990 (Box 19)
    - Legacy, 1948-1988 (Box 19)
    - Medical, 1971-1986 (Box 19)
    - Dachau, 1967-1990 (Box 19)
  - Holzapfel, Wilhelm, Die aus Finsternis Licht und aus Licht Finsternis machen (Box 19)
  - Kommunistische Partei Deutschlands (KPD)
    - Die Frau im Dritten Reich, 1931 (Box 19)
    - Christliches Landvolk und Kommunisten. Religion, Ehe, Familie, by Ernst Putz, 1931 (Box 19)
    - Stahlhelm für Diktatur, Arbeitsdienst, Streikbruch, Kriegsru¨stung, gegen Bolschewismus, 1931 (Box 19)
    - Wo bleibt der zweite Mann?, 1931 (Box 19)
    - Erwachendes Volk, 1931 (Box 19)
    - Das Los der Kriegskrüppel, 1919 (Box 19)
    - Wie verteidigt sich der Proletarier in politischen Strafsachen vor Polizei, Staatsanwaltschaft und Gericht?, 1931 (Box 19)
    - Und das Zentrum?, 1932 (Box 19)
    - Die rote Fahne, 1936 (Box 19)
    - Durch rote Einheit zur Macht, 1931 (Box 19)
    - Kampf um die Scholle: das Bauernhilfsprogramm der KPD, 1931 (Box 19)
    - Faschismus, 1931 January (Box 19)
    - Liebe, Geschlechtsbeziehungen und Geschlechtspolitik, 1930 (Box 19)
    - 4 Monate Brüning-Regierung: auf dem Wege zur faschistischen Diktatur: Nachtrag zum Handbuch ["21 Monate Hermann-Müller Regierung"] der Kommunistischen Reichstagsfraktion, 1930 (Box 19)
  - Kulka, Erich, Massenvernichtung der Juden wird verleugnet, 1993 (Box 19)
  - Political prisoners, 1976-1977 (Box 19)
  - Praemedicus, publication of the Association of Medical Societies, 1933-1985 (Box 19)
  - Veresaev, V. The Memoirs Of A Physician, (Tr. Simeon Linden), 1916 (Box 19)
  - Zentrum Partei re: pregnancy leave, 1985 (Box 19)
  - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands (SPD)
    - Jahrbuch der SPD, 1926-1929 (Box 19)
      - 1926
      - 1927 (Box 19)
      - 1928 (Box 19)
      - 1929 (Box 19)
    - Mutter und Säugling in der Gesetzgebung, Kommunale Praxis, 1925 (Box 19)
    - Sozialdemokratischer Parteitag 1927 in Kiel; Protokoll mit dem Bericht der Frauenkonferenz (Box 19)
    - Liebe verboten, 1932 (Box 20)
    - Kulturlehre des Sozialismus, by Gustav Radbruch, 1922 (Box 20)
  - Einsatzgruppen. Kaunas, Lithuania, 1941 October-December (Box 20)
  - Kampfreden und Aufsätze, by Ernst Thälmann, 1932 (Box 20)
  - Nietzsche, Friedrich
    - 1957 (Box 20)
    - Friedrich Nietzsche, by Frederick Copleston, 1975 (Box 20)
    - Nietzsches Werke, 1904-1950 (Box 20)
    - The Portable Nietzsche, by Walter Kaufmann, 1967-1972 (Box 20)
  - Nogar, Raymond. Lord of the Absurd, 1966 (Box 20)
  - Northrop, F.S.C. The Meeting Of East And West, 1974 (Box 20)
  - Nuremberg War Crimes Trials
    - American attitudes, 1970 (Box 20)
    - German views of the war trial, 1955-1984 (Box 20)
    - Legal, literary articles concerning trials, 1968-1996 (Box 20)
    - Reaching Judgment at Nuremberg, by Bradley F. Smith, 1977 (Box 20)
  - Paleontology, 1975 (Box 20)
  - Pascal, Blaise, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Poland, 1982-1986 (Box 20)
  - Thälmann, Ernst, Berliner Zeitung, 1985 (Box 20)
  - Bernard, Claude, 1960-1968 (Box 21)
  - Biographies from Hitler's Germany, 1968 (Box 21)
  - Biology (Box 21)
  - Bloch, Ernst, 1975 (Box 21)
  - Boll, Heinrich, 1987 (Box 21)
  - Book reviews, 1976-1987 (Box 21)
  - Brandt, Karl (Box 21)
  - Bremen, 1940-1987 (Box 21)
  - Conti, Leonard (Box 21)
  - Neonatology, 1976 (Box 21)
  - Neurophysiology, 1965-1989 (Box 21)
  - Wormser-Migot, Olga, Le système concentrationnaire nazi, 1968 (Box 21)
  - Taylor, Telford, Hitler's Secret Book, 1961 (Box 21)
  - van Roon, Ger, German Resistance To Hitler, 1971 (Box 21)
  - Virchow, Rudolf (Box 21)
  - West Germany: Right wing extremists, 1975 (Box 21)
  - Wheeler, Harvey, "Science's Slippery Slope", 1969-1975 (Box 21)
  - Witherspoon, Joseph, "Constitutional Concept of the Person and the Unborn Child" (Box 21)
  - The Works of Alfred Lord Tennyson (Box 21)
  - Yad Vashem, 1955 (Box 21)
  - Conference on Church and the Holocaust, Jerusalem, 1982 (Box 22)
  - Court cases
    - Jane E. Hodgson, et al., vs. Wendell Anderson, et al., 1974 (Box 22)
    - Jacobson vs. Massachusetts, 1905 (Box 22)
    - City of Kenosha vs. Peter Bruno, 1944-1973 (Box 22)
    - Edward Maher vs. Susan Roe, 1977 (Box 22)
    - John Poelker, et al. vs. Jane Doe, 1977 (Box 22)
    - Sierra Club vs. Morton, 1972 (Box 22)
    - Skinner vs. State of Oklahoma, 1942 (Box 22)
    - Singleton vs. Wulff, et. al., 1976 (Box 22)
    - Strunk vs. Strunk, 1969 (Box 22)
    - Doe vs. Bolton, 1973 (Box 22)
    - Morgentaler vs. The Queen (Canada), 1975 (Box 22)
    - United States vs. Rabinowitz, 1950 (Box 22)
    - United States vs. Schooner La Jeune Eugenie, 1822 (Box 22)
    - Furman vs. Georgia, 1972 (Box 22)
    - Bellotti vs. Baird, 1976 (Box 22)
  - Homosexuality Commission, Episcopal Diocese of Michigan, 1973 (Box 22)
  - Horvath, Tibor, "Euthanasia and the Criminal Law", 1972 (Box 22)
  - Hufeland, C.W., Enchiridion medicum; oder Anleitung zur medizinischen Praxis, 1857 (Box 22)
  - Humanist Manifesto, 1973 (Box 22)
  - Jaworski, Leon, After Fifteen Years, 1961 (Box 22)
  - Jescheck, Hans-Heinrich, Lehrbuch des Strafrechts: allgemeiner Teil, 1969 (Box 22)
  - Birth control, 1976-1982 (Box 23)
  - Bleuler, Eugen
    - Das autistisch-undisziplinierte Denken in der Medizin und seine Überwindung, 1927 (Box 23)
    - Der geborene Verbrecher: eine kritische Studie, 1896 (Box 23)
  - Blome, Kurt, Arzt im Kampf, 1942 (Box 23)
  - Bracher, Karl Dietrich, Die nationalsozialistische Machtergreifung, 1962 (Box 23)
  - Günther, Hans F.K., Platon als Hüter des Lebens, 1928 (Box 23)
  - Gurian, Waldemar, "Totalitarian Religions", 1952 (Box 23)
  - Gütt, Arthur
    - Dienst an der Rasse als Aufgabe der Staatspolitik, 1938 (Box 23)
    - Gesetz zur Verhütung erbkranken Nachwuchse, 1933 (Box 23)
  - Akten deutscher Bischöfe über die Lage der Kirche (Box 24)
  - Baumer, Franklin L. Religion and the Rise of Skepticism, 1960 (Box 24)
  - Bell, George, Bishop of Chichester, 1945-1978 (Box 24)
  - Bonhoeffer, Dietrich, 1967-1970 (Box 24)
    Includes notes by Carroll
  - Brunner, Emil, 1963 (Box 24)
  - Buttrick, George, 1997 (Box 24)
  - Catholic Church, 1961-1997 (Box 24)
  - Le Chambon-sur-Lignon, 1979-1996 (Box 24)
  - Orthodox Church, 1987 (Box 24)
  - Relationship with state, 1976-1988 (Box 24)
  - Vatican and World War II, 1940-1972 (Box 24)
  - Chadwick, Owen, The Secularization of the European Mind in the Nineteenth Century, 1975 (Box 25)
  - The Episcopal Synod Of America, 1989-1997 (Box 25)
  - Evangelical, 1989-1995 (Box 25)
  - Nazi persecution of the church, 1968 (Box 25)
  - Witness and welfare, 1981-1988 (Box 25)
  - Dostoevsky, Fyodor (Box 26)
  - Einstein, Albert (Box 26)
  - Fedorenko, Feodor, 1980 (Box 26)
  - Goldhagen, Erich, 1974 (Box 26)
  - Holocaust
    - Faith (Box 26)
    - General, 1852-1988 (Box 26)
    - Kristallnacht, 1978-1988 (Box 26)
    - Law and Medicine, 1984-1994 (Box 26)
    - Life, 1983 (Box 26)
    - Mein Kampf in Israel, 1992 (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 26)
    - Neo-Nazis, 1987-1988 (Box 26)
    - Psychology, 1974-1979 (Box 26)
    - Resistance, 1973-1993 (Box 26)
    - Revisionism, 1982 (Box 26)
    - Totalization (Box 26)
    - Wannsee Protocol, 1942 (Box 26)
  - Lewandowska, Maria, The History of My Family (Box 27)
  - Maimonides (Box 27)
  - Markus, R.A. The End of Ancient Christianity, 1990 (Box 27)
  - Morality, 1980-1982 (Box 27)
  - Mother Teresa, 1982 (Box 27)
  - Muggeridge, Malcolm (Box 27)
  - Neuhaus, Richard John, 1988-1990 (Box 27)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1984 (Box 27)
  - Niemöller, Martin, 1977-1992 (Box 27)
  - Niemöller, Wilhelm, 1949 (Box 27)
  - Noth, Gottfried (Box 27)
  - Novak, Michael, 1970 (Box 27)
  - Packer, J.I., Evangelism and the Sovereignty of God, 1961 (Box 27)
  - Pannenberg, Wolfhart, Christentum in einer säkularisierten Welt, 1988 (Box 27)
  - Papacy
    - Pope Pius XII, 1973-1991 (Box 27)
    - Pope John XXIII, 1976 (Box 27)
    - Pope Paul VI, 1974-1991 (Box 27)
    - Papal encyclicals, 1968-1974 (Box 27)
    - Pope Pius XI, 1937-1988 (Box 27)
    - Papal infallibility, 1976 (Box 27)
  - Pelikan, Jaroslav, 1984 (Box 27)
  - Polanyi, Michael, "Science and Man", 1970 (Box 27)
  - Poliakov, Leon, The History of Anti-Semitism, 1965 (Box 27)
  - Popieluszko, Jerzy, 1985 (Box 27)
  - Gardavský, Vítêzslav, Gott ist nicht ganz tot, 1970 (Box 28)
  - Guiness, Os, The American Hour, 1993 (Box 28)
  - Lapin, Daniel, 1991-1999 (Box 28)
  - Leibbrand, Werner and Annemarie Leibbrand-Wettley, 1979-1986 (Box 28)
    Includes letters from Leibrand-Wettley to Carroll
  - Lewis, C.S., 1979-1987 (Box 28)
  - Lindbeck, George, 1972 (Box 28)
  - Man as machine, 1975-1976 (Box 28)
  - Medawar, Peter (Box 28)
  - Nuremberg trials
    - Andrus, Burton, The Infamous at Nuremberg, 1969 (Box 28)
    - Brandt, Karl, 1986-1987 (Box 28)
    - U.S. vs. Karl Brandt (Case 1), 1946-1993 (Box 28)
    - U.S. vs. Josef Altstoetter (Case 3) (Box 28)
    - U.S. vs. Oswald Pohl (Case 4) (Box 28)
    - U.S. vs. Friedrich Flick (Case 5) (Box 28)
    - U.S. vs. Carl Krauch (Case 6), 1977-1979 (Box 28)
    - U.S. vs. Ulrich Greifelt (Case 8), 1943-1977 (Box 28)
    - U.S. vs. Otto Ohlendorf (Case 9) (Box 28)
    - U.S. vs. Alfried Krupp (Case 10), 1950 (Box 28)
  - Leibbrand, Werner, 1968 (Box 29)
  - Lenz, Adolf, Grundriss der Kriminalbiologie, table of contents, 1927 (Box 29)
  - Lewis, C.S., 1954 (Box 29)
  - Lutheran Church, Evangelisch-Lutherische Kirchenzeitung: Festausgabe aus Anlass der Vollversammlung des Lutherischen Weltbundes Minneapolis, 1957 (Box 29)
  - Mauthausen, "Bericht über Gesundheitspflege für die Häftlinge in Mauthausen" (Box 29)
  - Music (Box 29)
  - Orwell, George, 1961 (Box 29)
  - Österreich (Austria), 1974 (Box 29)
  - Pagès, Jeanne, Le contrôle des naissances en France et à l'étranger, 1971 (Box 29)
  - Pasternak, Boris (Box 29)
  - Poland, 1946 (Box 29)
  - Pompey, Heinrich (Box 29)
  - Radbruch, Gustav, Der innere Weg: Aufriss meines Lebens, 1951 (Box 29)
  - Schmitt, Carl, 1983 (Box 29)
  - Walter, Franz, Die Euthanasie und die Heiligkeit des Lebens: Die Lebensvernichtung im Dienste der Medizin und Eugenik nach christlicher und monistischer Ethik, 1935 (Box 29)
  - Kamisar, Yale, 1953-1976 (Box 30)
  - Kepler, Milton, 1968 (Box 30)
  - Kessler, Harry, Graf, 1971 (Box 30)
  - Klemperer, Victor, 1946 (Box 30)
  - Kolbe, Maximilian, 1971-1983 (Box 30)
  - Kriminalsoziologie, 1933 (Box 30)
  - Laternser, Hans, Die andere Seite im Auschwitz-Prozess 1963/65: Reden eines Verteidigers, 1966 (Box 30)
  - Leclercq, Jacques, Les grandes lignes de la philosophie morale, 1946 (Box 30)
  - Nagel, W.H., 1971 (Box 30)
  - Nathanson, Bernard, on abortion, 1973-1976 (Box 30)
  - Nazis
    - "Lonely and Full of Hate, She Joined the Nazi Party", 1974 (Box 30)
    - "Utilitarian Reasoning in Nazi Medical Policy", 1975 (Box 30)
  - Noonan, John T., on abortion, 1973-1976 (Box 30)
  - Roe vs. Wade, 1972 (Box 30)
  - Santa Clara County vs. Southern Pacific Railroad, 1883-1885 (Box 30)
  - Bevölkerungsfragen, 1935-1936 (Box 31)
  - Bibliographies, 1940-1977 (Box 31)
  - Binding, Karl, Lehrbuch des gemeinen deutschen Strafrechts, 1902 (Box 31)
  - Medical morals, 1955 (Box 31)
  - Moll, Albert, Årztliche Ethik unter besonderer Berücksichtigung der Psychotherapie und Psychohygiene, 1902 (Box 31)
  - Monod, Jacques, 1974-1975 (Box 31)
  - Moral theology, 1962 (Box 31)
  - Cassirer, Ernst, 1978 (Box 32)
  - Finnis, John, Natural Law and Natural Right, 1982 (Box 32)
  - Hart, H.L.A., The Concept of Law, 1961 (Box 32)
  - Henkys, Reinhard, 1964 (Box 32)
  - Hermens, Ferdinand A., 1975-1976 (Box 32)
  - Ihering, Rudolf von, Law as a Means to an End, 1968 (Box 32)
  - Jäger, Herbert, Verbrechen unter totalitärer Herrschaft, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Laserson, Max, 1980 (Box 32)
  - Law, 1975-1987 (Box 32)
  - Levinson, Sanford, "The Specious Morality of the Law", 1977 (Box 32)
  - Oakeshott, Michael, 1975-1983 (Box 32)
  - Paulson, Stanley L., 1973 (Box 32)
  - Plutarch (Box 32)
  - Radbruch, Gustav, Die Abtreibung der Leibesfrucht: zwei Gutachten, 1921 (Box 32)
  - Rogat, Yosal, 1964 (Box 32)